Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Mr.
Speaker 2: President. The Senator from Missouri is recognized.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Reserving the right to object, now that I have the floor, the Senator of Hawaii answered a question: Do you agree with this administration's policy to deny MIGS to
the Ukrainians?
The
Speaker 3: Senators may not interrogate other
Speaker 4: Senators. Is there an objection? The Senator may not interrogate other Senators.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Well, the Senator doesn't want to answer any questions I see. He denied my request to ask him a question a moment ago. Is there an objection? He's silent now when he can answer. Are you not going to let me speak?
Speaker 5: Does he object
or
Speaker 6: not? The regular order has been called. Is there
objection?
Speaker 7: I object.
The objection is heard.
The
Speaker 7: objection is heard.
Speaker 8: The senator from Missouri is recognized.
Speaker 9: Thank you, Mr. President. Thank you for finally giving me an option to speak. It's interesting the senator will come to the floor, but he doesn't want to engage in a colloquy. He doesn't want to answer questions. But let's talk a little bit about the policy, the disastrous foreign policy that he is supporting.
This is
Speaker 9: the White House's latest talking points that their failure in Ukraine is now due to some logistics problem in the Department of Defense that, of course, they can't be responsible for
what
Speaker 10: they're doing. Just like they're not responsible for anything. They're not responsible for what happened in Afghanistan, their policy. They're not responsible for what's happened in Ukraine, their policy. Let's talk about their policy in Ukraine that the senator seems to favor but
Speaker 12: doesn't want to answer questions about.
Speaker 11: Mr. President, will the senator yield to
a
Speaker 12: question?
Speaker 12: What has President Zelensky been asking for for weeks, indeed months, on end? He said send us planes. What has this administration done? No. Actually, first they said yes, then they said maybe, then they said no. Today, the Secretary of Defense testified before the Armed Services Committee, under oath,
even
Speaker 12: though this Congress has appropriated $3 billion in military lethal aid to the people of Ukraine, the Defense Department has so far given them less than a third of it. Why? Because of logistics? No. He was asked that. No. Because of policy. His comment was, we are giving them what we think they need. Mr. President, I would just point out that that's not what the Ukrainians think.
Speaker 12: If you listen to President Zelensky,
if
Speaker 10: you listen to the Ukrainian parliamentarians who have been here, if you talk to them, what they'll say is they need more
Speaker 12: military aid. They need more help. This administration won't give it to them, not because of logistics, but because of policy. We don't have a logistics problem. We have a Joe Biden problem, and we've had that problem in Ukraine from day one. This administration's policy was to deter a Russian invasion of Ukraine.
Speaker 12: It failed. Why did it fail? It's not hard to see. President Biden came to
Speaker 13: office. What did he do? When Ukraine asked for military assistance, -Will
Speaker 11: the senator yield? -he denied it. Can we have order, Mr. President? -I'm just
Speaker 14: asking, will the senator yield? -Can we have order, Mr. President?
Speaker 15: -Senator from Missouri has the
floor.
Speaker 12: -When Joe Biden came to office, the people of Ukraine asked for military assistance a year ago, a year ago. Did he give it to them? No.
He
Speaker 12: denied them military assistance. He denied them lethal aid. What did he do, though, for Vladimir Putin?
When he
Speaker 12: came to office, he green-lighted Vladimir Putin's pipeline. He turned their pipelines on, he turned our pipelines off. What did he do with American energy production? He throttled it down. He turned it
off.
Speaker 9: His first actions in office.
Speaker 9: were to, among other things, cancel the Keystone Pipeline, halt the leasing program in ANWR, issue a halt to new oil and gas leases and drilling permits on federal lands, impose tougher regulations on oil and gas and methane emissions, and a host of new regulations on other energy production. And that had the desired effect. Russian energy production up. Russian revenues up. What's happened since then, since the invasion of Ukraine? Well, it's been one gaffe after another.
He
Speaker 9: won't send them planes. Today, the Secretary of Defense also confirmed that this administration has, in fact, not been sharing intelligence with the Ukrainians. In fact, today, the Secretary of Defense had to admit that the administration was going to be forced to change policy, his words, change policy in Ukraine, because, in fact, we had not been sharing all the intelligence we might have
with
Speaker 9: Ukrainian soldiers and the Ukrainian military, despite their request from it. Whose decision was that? Joe Biden's. It's his policy.
The president,
Speaker 12: though, hasn't been entirely silent.
He did have
Speaker 12: this to say, for God's sake, this man cannot remain in power.
So now Joe Biden
Speaker 12: doesn't appear to know whether we're fighting to or struggling to help the
Speaker 9: Ukrainians defend themselves or whether we're launching a war of regime change in Russia itself.
Okay.
You know,
Speaker 9: Mr. President, the bottom line is this: on one issue after another, when it comes to Ukraine, this president has been wrong on every aspect of policy that has mattered, he has been wrong.
Is it
Speaker 9: any wonder the Ukrainians are saying change policy, share your intelligence, send us the aid that we have requested?
Speaker 9: I say again, we don't have a logistics problem. The White House shouldn't point fingers and shift the blame. We have a Joe Biden problem.
That's the nub
Speaker 9: of the issue here.
Well, then
Speaker 9: there was Joe Biden's comment that it's sounding like we're going to send ground troops. You're going to see when you go there, he said to U.S. service members, when you go there, and
some of
Speaker 9: you have been there, you're going to see women, young people standing in front of a damn tank just saying, I'm not leaving, I'm holding my ground, right?
The
Speaker 9: president, it's one gaffe after another. It's one switch in policy after another. It's a disaster from beginning to end. And let's not forget where these foreign policy disasters really kicked off in a big way. Yeah, it was in Afghanistan. And am I concerned about Afghanistan? You're darn right I am. 13 service members were killed at Abbey Gate, including one from my home state. And I will never forget talking to his
father
As soon
Speaker 9: as we learned of the attack, before in fact his son's, the official notice of his son's death had been released. And his father asked me to do everything in my power to hold this administration accountable, and that is exactly what I'm going to do.
Now, has
Speaker 9: anyone been held accountable yet for Afghanistan? Has somebody been fired? Has somebody been relieved of command?
Nope. Has
Speaker 9: somebody been shown the door? Nope.
Has
Speaker 9: there been a change in policy at the Department of Defense? No, we just stumble from one crisis to another. Why? Because we have a Joe Biden problem. Now, this administration is doing exactly what their commander-in-chief wants them to do, and it is wrong again and again and again and again. So, Mr. President...
Until
Speaker 9: we see some change in policy from this administration, until this Senate gets serious about its oversight responsibilities at the Department of Defense, I'm going to ask that for senior defense leaders, we at least observe regular order. I can't block a nomination. I can't halt it.
But I can ask
Speaker 9: that regular order be followed.
And
Speaker 9: that's exactly what I'm going to ask with regard to this nomination and other senior leaders until there is accountability, until we have a change in policy, and until this administration admits that on issue after issue, in virtually every aspect of its foreign policy, it's just dead wrong. I yield for it.